[{"question_number": "Q29", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "child presents with symptoms suggestive of multiple sclerosis (MS). What is the most significant risk factor for developing MS?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 1 2021_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2021, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q30", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Intravenous methylprednisolone (1,000 mg for 5 days)", "B": "Plasma exchange for severe or refractory deficits", "C": "A slow prednisone tapered therapy", "D": "Oral azathioprine maintenance therapy"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 1 2021_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2021, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q37", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Anti-GLUR3", "B": "Anti-NMDA", "C": "Anti-GAD", "D": "Anti-CASPR2"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 1 2021_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2021, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q57", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Observe", "B": "Start treatment", "C": "Perform MRI after 3 months", "D": "Refer for physical therapy"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part 1 2021_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2021, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q62", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Start Natalizumab", "B": "Continue Interferon", "C": "Start Glatiramer acetate", "D": "Start corticosteroids"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 1 2021_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2021, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q65", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Stiff person syndrome", "B": "Multiple sclerosis", "C": "Parkinson\u2019s disease", "D": "Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 1 2021_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2021, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q71", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "ACE level", "B": "JC virus PCR", "C": "Anti-JCV antibodies", "D": "Repeat MRI in 3 months"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Part 1 2021_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2021, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q85", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Multiple Sclerosis", "B": "Sarcoidosis", "C": "Neuromyelitis Optica", "D": "Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part 1 2021_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2021, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q87", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Anti-GQ", "B": "Anti-GM", "C": "Anti-ganglionic Acetylcholine antibody", "D": "Anti-Hu antibody"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Part 2 - 2023_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2023, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q88", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Susac syndrome", "B": "Kearns-Sayre syndrome", "C": "Multiple Sclerosis", "D": "Myasthenia Gravis"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 2 - 2023_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2023, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q91", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "25%", "B": "50%", "C": "72%", "D": "0%"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 2 2020 copy_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2020, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q103", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Leg weakness"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 2 2020 copy_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2020, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q106", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "0.2%", "B": "16%", "C": "2%", "D": "90%"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part 2 2020 copy_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2020, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q112", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Use is encouraged", "B": "Use should be avoided if possible", "C": "Use is mandatory", "D": "No recommendation is given"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part 2 2020 copy_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2020, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q122", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Pulse steroid course", "B": "Beta-interferon therapy", "C": "Amantadine", "D": "Plasma exchange"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part II 2018_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2018, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q123", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "patient diagnosed with multiple sclerosis and started on disease-modifying therapy (DMT) one year later had a relapse. MRI shows long extensive spinal hyperintensity of the spinal cord with an axial view showing a trident sign. What is the pathophysiology of this diagnosis?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 2 Adult Neurology residency 2024 V9_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q127", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "16-year-old with symptoms of optic neuritis and brain MRI showing bilateral extensive enhancement in the optic nerve, with the rest of the MRI normal, what is the diagnosis? (No NMOSD in the choices)"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 2 Adult Neurology residency 2024 V9_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q140", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Start fingolimod", "B": "Start beta interferon", "C": "Observation while doing more confirmatory tests", "D": "Reassure her"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part I 2018_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2018, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q148", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Cleft palate", "B": "Transient leukocytosis", "C": "Immunosuppression", "D": "Premature labor"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part I 2018_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2018, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q150", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "patient with one clinical attack of multiple sclerosis has:"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part I 2018_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2018, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q153", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "No disease-modifying therapy (DMT)", "B": "Start DMT", "C": "Observation only", "D": "Immediate hospitalization"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part I 2018_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2018, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q158", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Multiple Sclerosis", "B": "Clinically Isolated Syndrome (CIS)", "C": "Radiologically Isolated Syndrome (RIS)", "D": "Neuromyelitis Optica"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part I 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q162", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "7-year-old boy has recurrent focal seizures involving the right side of his body. Sometimes, these evolve to epilepsia partialis continua. On examination, he has right-sided weakness and his MRI shows perisylvian atrophy. Which of the following antibodies is likely to be present in his CSF?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part I 2022_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2022, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q163", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Fingolimod", "B": "Teriflunomide", "C": "Natalizumab", "D": "Dimethyl fumarate"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part I 2023_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2023, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q170", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Microglia", "B": "Neurons", "C": "Oligodendrocytes", "D": "Astrocytes"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Part I 2022_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2022, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q202", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Guillain-Barr\u00e9 syndrome", "B": "Miller Fisher syndrome", "C": "Bickerstaff brainstem encephalitis", "D": "Multiple sclerosis"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q217", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Continue treatment", "B": "Discontinue treatment", "C": "Decrease the rate", "D": "Administer antihistamines and monitor closely"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q239", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Ach antibodies", "B": "Anti-GM1 antibodies", "C": "Cortical dementia", "D": "Moyamoya disease"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q240", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Miller Fisher syndrome", "B": "Bickerstaff brainstem encephalitis", "C": "Guillain-Barr\u00e9 syndrome", "D": "Multiple sclerosis"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q246", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Multiple sclerosis", "B": "Neuromyelitis optica (NMO)", "C": "Transverse myelitis", "D": "Brain tumor"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q249", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Migraine", "B": "Intracranial hemorrhage", "C": "Multiple sclerosis", "D": "Neuro-Behcet's disease"}, "correct_answer": "D", "source_file": "Promotion 2022_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Promotion", "exam_year": 2022, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q252", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Alemtuzumab", "B": "Dalfampridine", "C": "Dimethyl fumarate", "D": "Fingolimod"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q255", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Peripheral brainstem", "B": "Inferior temporal pole", "C": "Ovoid periventricular", "D": "Cerebellar atrophy"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q258", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "SSES", "B": "VEP", "C": "BSEP", "D": "MRI"}, "correct_answer": "D", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q259", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Cervical region", "B": "Thoracic region", "C": "Lumbar region", "D": "Sacral region"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q263", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Hemiplegic migraine", "B": "HaNDL", "C": "DAVF", "D": "Viral meningitis"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q264", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Lesions in the frontal lobe are most predictive.", "B": "Infratentorial and spinal cord lesions are most predictive.", "C": "Lesion volume is irrelevant.", "D": "Only the number of lesions matters."}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q268", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Alemtuzumab", "B": "Fingolimod", "C": "Natalizumab", "D": "Ocrelizumab"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part II 2022_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2022, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q270", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Contrast enhancement for 3 months", "B": "LETM", "C": "Multiple small ovoid lesions in periventricular white matter", "D": "Dawson\u2019s fingers on MRI"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part II 2022_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2022, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q272", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Relapsing-Remitting Multiple Sclerosis (RRMS)", "B": "Primary Progressive Multiple Sclerosis (PPMS)", "C": "Secondary Progressive Multiple Sclerosis (SPMS)", "D": "Clinically Isolated Syndrome (CIS)"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part II 2022_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2022, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q275", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "child presents with decreased vision in both eyes, papilledema, and no confusion. An orbital MRI shows anterior bilateral optic nerve enhancement. What is the diagnosis?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part II 2022_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2022, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q284", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Adolescent obesity", "B": "Epstein-Barr virus seropositivity", "C": "Smoking", "D": "Vitamin D deficiency"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Promotion 2018_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Promotion", "exam_year": 2018, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q302", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "52%", "B": "58%", "C": "60%", "D": "65%"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Promotion 2018_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Promotion", "exam_year": 2018, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q309", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Fingolimod", "B": "Interferon", "C": "Dalfampridine", "D": "Ocrelizumab"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Promotion 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Promotion", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q310", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Relapsing-Remitting Multiple Sclerosis (RRMS)", "B": "Neuromyelitis Optica (NMO)", "C": "Acute Disseminated Encephalomyelitis (ADEM)", "D": "Myelin Oligodendrocyte Glycoprotein Antibody Disease (MOGAD)"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Promotion 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Promotion", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q311", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "30-year-old man with migraine with incidental periventricular lesion and 2 spine lesions with negative OCB", "B": "31-year-old woman with migraine, 4 pericallosal and 3 cerebellar plaques but normal spine", "C": "52-year-old woman with demyelinating lesion in the brain and OCB in serum", "D": "28-year-old woman with optic neuritis and positive oligoclonal bands in CSF"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Promotion 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Promotion", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q313", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Acetazolamide", "B": "Carbamazepine", "C": "Diazepam", "D": "Baclofen"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Promotion 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Promotion", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q316", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "young patient presents with a history of encephalopathy, weakness, and hearing loss. An MRI of the brain is performed. Which condition is most likely indicated by these symptoms?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Promotion 2021_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Promotion", "exam_year": 2021, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q331", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Intracerebral hemorrhage", "B": "Cerebral venous thrombosis", "C": "PRES", "D": "Lupus Cerebritis"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Promotion 2022_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Promotion", "exam_year": 2022, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q357", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Stop fingolimod", "B": "Start steroid", "C": "Plasmapheresis (PLEX)", "D": "Order ophthalmology evaluation"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Promotion 2023_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Promotion", "exam_year": 2023, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q371", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Persistent enhancement more than 3 months", "B": "Oligoclonal bands in cerebrospinal fluid", "C": "Dawson\u2019s fingers on MRI", "D": "Relapsing-remitting neurological symptoms"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "part 2 2024_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q372", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "No treatment needed", "B": "Pulse steroids", "C": "Plasma exchange", "D": "IVIG"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "part 2 2024_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q375", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Multiple sclerosis", "B": "Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder (NMOSD)", "C": "MOG Antibody Disease (MOGAD)", "D": "Ischemic optic neuropathy"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "part 2 2024_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q378", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Alemtuzumab", "B": "Fingolimod", "C": "Ocrelizumab", "D": "Dimethyl fumarate"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "part 2 2024_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q379", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Alemtuzumab", "B": "Fingolimod", "C": "Natalizumab", "D": "Ocrelizumab"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "part 2 2024_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q380", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Sarcoidosis", "B": "Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder", "C": "Spinal cord infarction", "D": "Chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "part 2 2024_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q381", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "Rebound disease", "B": "Pseudo relapse", "C": "True relapse", "D": "Urinary tract infection"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "part 2 2024_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q1", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "patient with multiple sclerosis presented with leg weakness that improved with steroids but recurred after one week. What is the next step in management?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "PART I - 2024 - KSMC Revision_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q13", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "woman with multiple sclerosis on fingolimod has a brain MRI showing new active lesions in the left frontal lobe. What is the most appropriate next step in management?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 1 2020_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2020, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q152", "question_text": "Which of the following has an indication in multiple sclerosis disease progression?", "options": {"A": "Cortical atrophy", "B": "T2 lesions", "C": "Gadolinium-enhancing lesions", "D": "T1 lesions"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part I 2018_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2018, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q97", "question_text": "In the same scenario of the young female with sudden left-sided weakness, what would you give for her symptoms over the last 5 days?", "options": {"A": "Pulse steroid", "B": "Aspirin", "C": "Intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG)", "D": "Oral antibiotics"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 2 2020 copy_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2020, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q6", "question_text": "In which case would steroids have an effect?", "options": {"A": "Brain cancer with vasogenic edema", "B": "Traumatic brain injury", "C": "Multiple sclerosis", "D": "Alzheimer's disease"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Part 1 2020_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2020, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q6", "question_text": "In which case would steroids have an effect?", "options": {"A": "Brain cancer with vasogenic edema", "B": "Traumatic brain injury", "C": "Multiple sclerosis", "D": "Alzheimer's disease"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Part 1 2020_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2020, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q124", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "patient with optic neuritis symptoms and brain MRI showing multiple white matter lesions periventricular, which of the following is true?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 2 Adult Neurology residency 2024 V9_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q248", "question_text": "In patients with high-risk clinically isolated syndrome (CIS), which of the following factors is predictive of future rapid disability worsening as measured by EDSS?", "options": {"A": "Younger age", "B": "Absence of disease-modifying treatment (DMT)", "C": "Presence of T2 lesions", "D": "Older age"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q269", "question_text": "Which symptom indicates worsening in primary progressive multiple sclerosis (PPMS)?", "options": {"A": "Leg weakness", "B": "Upper limb weakness", "C": "Fatigue", "D": "Visual disturbances"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part II 2022_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2022, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q220", "question_text": "Which of the following is considered a red flag in multiple sclerosis (MS)?", "options": {"A": "Bilateral internuclear ophthalmoplegia (INO)", "B": "Extensive transverse myelitis (TM)", "C": "Enhancing lesion greater than 3 months", "D": "Complete gaze palsy"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q58", "question_text": "AQP4-IgG is a specific, pathogenic biomarker of which condition?", "options": {"A": "Multiple Sclerosis", "B": "Neuromyelitis Optica Spectrum Disorder (NMOSD)", "C": "Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis", "D": "Guillain-Barr\u00e9 Syndrome"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part 1 2021_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2021, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q385", "question_text": "What is the risk of multiple sclerosis (MS) in 15 years if there is a history of optic neuritis and several T2 supratentorial lesions?", "options": {"A": "50% with need to start DMT", "B": "30% with need to start DMT", "C": "30% without need to start DMT", "D": "10% with no MRI lesions"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "part 2 2024_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q177", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "young male had an isolated single attack of focal neurological deficit and did not start on DMT. What is the percentage chance of having a second attack?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part I 2023_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2023, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q23", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "male patient with limbic encephalitis (seizures, psychosis) is asked about the most common antibody associated with this condition. Which of the following is the answer?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 1 2021_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2021, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q128", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "patient diagnosed with Multiple Sclerosis is being evaluated. What would be a favorable factor in her case?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 2 Adult Neurology residency 2024 V9_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q144", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "19-year-old female presented with a history of seizures. One month before presentation, she had depression, social isolation, personality changes, and hallucinations. She was taken to a psychiatrist and was given antipsychotic medications. The examination was unremarkable except for orofacial dyskinesia. What is the most likely diagnosis?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part I 2018_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2018, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q154", "question_text": "Which of the following MRI characteristics is the best predictor of future disability in patients with multiple sclerosis?", "options": {"A": "Baseline enhancing lesion number", "B": "Baseline T2 lesion number", "C": "Baseline T2 lesion volume", "D": "Number of new enhancing lesions"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Part I 2018_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2018, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q306", "question_text": "Which of the following treatments causes rebound multiple sclerosis (MS) if stopped?", "options": {"A": "Fingolimod", "B": "Alemtuzumab", "C": "Ocrelizumab", "D": "Dimethyl fumarate"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Promotion 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Promotion", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q373", "question_text": "What is the most important risk factor for multiple sclerosis (MS)?", "options": {"A": "Epstein-Barr virus (EBV)", "B": "Smoking", "C": "Vitamin D deficiency", "D": "Family history of MS"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "part 2 2024_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q273", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "patient was treated for multiple sclerosis and presents with myelitis, showing a trident sign and LETM with expansile and avidly enhancing dorsal cord on imaging. What is the likely etiology?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part II 2022_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2022, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q245", "question_text": "What type of cell is primarily involved in MS lesions?", "options": {"A": "T cell", "B": "B cell", "C": "Eosinophils", "D": "Neutrophils"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q156", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "female with pure sensory neuropathy and NCS showing demyelinating neuropathy is likely to have:"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part I 2018_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2018, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q282", "question_text": "Which of the following is a characteristic of primary progressive multiple sclerosis according to McDonald criteria 2017?", "options": {"A": "39-year-old man with progressive symptoms over 2 months with periventricular hyperintense lesion", "B": "30-year-old man with progressive symptoms over one year", "C": "40-year-old with progressive ataxia over one year and T2 hyperintensity with no oligoclonal bands (OCB)", "D": "39-year-old man with progressive symptoms over 12 months, cortical hyperintense lesion, and OCB"}, "correct_answer": "D", "source_file": "Promotion 2018_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Promotion", "exam_year": 2018, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q121", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "patient was diagnosed with Multiple Sclerosis for 8 months, based on an initial attack of transverse myelitis causing lower limb symptoms. Now she is pregnant and off disease-modifying therapy (DMT). She presented with lower limb numbness and reported a change in her urine smell and odor. What is the diagnosis?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 2 Adult Neurology residency 2024 V9_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q253", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "female patient with MS on glatiramer acetate wants to take the flu vaccine. What is the best recommendation?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q20", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "patient with relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis has had no disease activity for two years. What is the percentage of benign multiple sclerosis?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 1 2020_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2020, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q80", "question_text": "Gadolinium contrast enhancement is present in essentially all cases of which condition?", "options": {"A": "Multiple Sclerosis", "B": "Neuromyelitis Optica Spectrum Disorder (NMOSD)", "C": "Acute Disseminated Encephalomyelitis", "D": "Transverse Myelitis"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Part 1 2021_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2021, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q101", "question_text": "For patients without brain lesions at the onset of optic neuritis, when was the risk of developing MS greatest?", "options": {"A": "First year", "B": "First 5 years", "C": "Between 10 and 15 years", "D": "After 15 years"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part 2 2020 copy_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2020, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q129", "question_text": "Which DMT causes ITP? (attached picture of purpura)", "options": {"A": "Alemtuzumab", "B": "Fingolimod", "C": "Natalizumab", "D": "Ocrelizumab"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 2 Adult Neurology residency 2024 V9_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q271", "question_text": "An MS patient with a history of recurrent relapses has been stable on natalizumab for the past 7 months. However, he has started to show signs of confusion, suggestive of progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy (PML). What should be done next?", "options": {"A": "Check JCV antibodies", "B": "Brain MRI with contrast", "C": "Discontinue natalizumab immediately", "D": "Perform lumbar puncture for JC virus PCR"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part II 2022_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2022, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q115", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "patient presents with autonomic dysfunction and pupillary changes (miosis). What is the antibody associated with this condition?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 2 2020 copy_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2020, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q92", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "woman who had repeated episodes of vomiting for one month visited the ER and was given omeprazole. She experienced visual changes in both eyes at different times. Now, she presents with symptoms of transverse myelitis (TM). What is the diagnosis?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 2 2020 copy_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2020, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q95", "question_text": "In patients with optic neuritis, what was the risk of developing MS when MRI evidence of prior demyelination was present?", "options": {"A": "25%", "B": "50%", "C": "72%", "D": "16%"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Part 2 2020 copy_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2020, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q125", "question_text": "What DMT has a 30% increased risk of secondary autoimmune disorders?", "options": {"A": "Alemtuzumab", "B": "Fingolimod", "C": "Ocrelizumab", "D": "Natalizumab"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 2 Adult Neurology residency 2024 V9_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q173", "question_text": "The periventricular white lesion typical of multiple sclerosis (MS) follows a specific pattern in the distribution of which following structure?", "options": {"A": "Oligodendrocyte cell body", "B": "Arterioles", "C": "Venules", "D": "Capillaries"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Part I 2023_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2023, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q17", "question_text": "Which of the following is considered a red flag in multiple sclerosis?", "options": {"A": "Partial myelitis", "B": "Decreased facial sensation", "C": "Complete ophthalmoplegia", "D": "Erectile dysfunction"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Part 1 2020_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2020, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q143", "question_text": "Typical multiple sclerosis (MS) presentation includes one or more episodes of:", "options": {"A": "Unilateral optic neuritis", "B": "Painless binocular diplopia", "C": "Focal brainstem or cerebellar syndrome", "D": "Partial transverse myelitis with sensory and/or motor symptoms"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part I 2018_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2018, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q359", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "patient with a known case of Multiple Sclerosis (MS) used a medication that causes flushing. What is the mechanism of action of that drug?"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "part 2 2021 (2", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2021, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q3", "question_text": "An MS patient on disease-modifying therapy (DMT) lost follow-up and presented to the ER with low platelets and a skin rash. What medication might they be on?", "options": {"A": "Ofatumumab", "B": "Alemtuzumab", "C": "Fingolimod", "D": "Natalizumab"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "PART I - 2024 - KSMC Revision_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2024, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q243", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "IVIG", "B": "Steroid", "C": "Plasmapheresis", "D": "Discontinuation of Natalizumab"}, "correct_answer": "C", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q247", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "It is optional", "B": "It is standard", "C": "It is contraindicated", "D": "It is only for severe cases"}, "correct_answer": "B", "source_file": "Part II 2019_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part II", "exam_year": 2019, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q33", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "High-dose corticosteroids", "B": "Immediate temporal artery biopsy", "C": "Nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs)", "D": "Observation and follow-up"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part 1 2020_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2020, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}, {"question_number": "Q171", "question_text": "", "options": {"A": "OCB testing", "B": "Rituximab therapy", "C": "ANCA and anti-dsDNA testing", "D": "Lymphoma evaluation"}, "correct_answer": "A", "source_file": "Part I 2022_mcqs.txt", "exam_type": "Part I", "exam_year": 2022, "subspecialty": "Neuroimmunology", "explanation": ""}]